Wait a minute!
等会儿 等会儿 等会儿
What is this?
这啥呀
A friendship letter!
交友信
Why are you so surprised?
至于这么惊讶吗
Isn't it natural for me
我收到这种交友信
to receive such a letter?
那不是天经地义的吗
In my previous school,
我在上个学校
such letters I received
收到这种信
could fill a burlap bag.
都是拿麻袋装的
See?
看好了啊
Just in two days.
刚来两天
Read it for me.
你帮我看看
-You know that. -I know, Jinghui.
你知道 灰哥 我知道
[Show me.]
给我看看
[Forget it, maybe later.]
别看了 回头再看吧
[Naive.]
少见多怪的
Qingtian,
晴天
how could it be with Lan Jinghui?
信怎么会在兰靖灰身上
I placed it on
我明明是放
Ling Dong's desk.
凌冬那儿了呀
The letter
信的内容
must not be seen by Jinghui.
千万不能被他看见
Or there is nothing
要不然我跳进黄河
I can do to explain.
都解释不清了
Xiao Xiaohua,
肖小画
I know your secret,
我知道你的秘密
and I'll make it public.
我要告诉全世界
What should I do, Qingtian?
晴天 怎么办啊
It's okay, Xiaohua,
没事 小画
take a candy and calm down.
先吃颗糖冷静一下
Yes, we must find a way
对 一定要想办法把信
to retrieve the letter.
从他那儿拿回来
I would rather my admiration
我宁愿崇拜凌冬的心
for Ling Dong be buried forever,
永远不见天日
which is better than being threatened.
总比被兰靖灰给威胁好
Well,
那
what should we do?
那 怎么办
Listen, here's my plan.
我有办法 咱们这样
Just one look, Jinghui.
灰哥 你给我看一眼
Just a glance.
就一眼 灰哥
Um,
那个什么
come with me, come on.
你跟我来一趟 快快快
Why?
干嘛呀
You'll know.
去了你就知道了
I'm going, too.
我也去
Save it.
你一边待着去
Why are you in such a hurry?
干嘛去啊 这么急
You'll know.
你来了你就知道
Ma Yiming,
马一鸣同学
could you please help me
能不能麻烦你
buy a bottle of milk?
帮我买瓶牛奶
I can't.
不能
Why?
为什么
You're not as beautiful as Xu Mengyu.
因为你没有徐梦予好看
Buy it for me!
买
Hey, hold on.
不是 不是 不是
Why are you in such a hurry?
徒弟 这么着急去干嘛
Didn't you promise me to
师父 你不是说要教我
teach me how to ride a bicycle?
学自行车吗
Right now?
现在
How can I teach you
现在没有自行车
without a bicycle now? After school.
我怎么教你 放学吧
Wait, I mean,
等等 师父 那个什么
you can teach me the action of riding.
你可以先教我学动作
That's right.
对 动作
Come with me.
跟我来
The key is to
骑自行车最关键的
make flexible leg movements.
就是腿部一定要灵活
It's important to use waist and belly.
腰腹力量同样重要
Upper limb strength cannot be ignored.
上肢力量更加不可忽视
Cannot!
不可忽视
Of course,
当然
the most important thing
学自行车
of riding a bicycle
最重要的因素就是
is balance.
平衡性
Alright.
算了
I don't think I can make it.
我觉得我是学不会了
Maybe next time.
下次再说吧
Hold on,
不是 徒弟
balance is very important.
平衡性是很重要的
Let me switch to a simpler method.
不行我跟你换一招
I have a
我有更简单
more basic way
我有更基础的
to get started.
入门方式嘛
He took it away.
他拿走了
What, how do you know?
什么 你怎么知道啊
Ling Dong, can you...
凌冬 能不能
No.
不能
Why?
为什么
It has nothing to do with me.
这事跟我没关系
It has everything to do with you!
这跟你有关系
What is the probability that
例如我抛掷一枚骰子
[I roll a dice with a number]
出现点数小于三的概率
[less than three?]
是多少
[Guys, please tell me,]
我想问一下同学们
[what is the number]
谁能告诉我
[less than three]
一点到六点中
[in numbers one to six?]
小于三的点数是什么
[Chen Luyang, please.]
陈璐阳
[One and two.]
一点和二点
[Correct.]
对了
[So what is the probability]
那么出现一点的概率
[of the number 1 appearing?]
是多少呢
[It's one-sixth.]
六分之一
[Similarly,]
同样
[the probability of 2 is one-sixth.]
两点也是六分之一
[Analogously,]
那么同样的
[the probability of 3 or 5 occurring]
三点和五点
is also one-sixth.
也一样是六分之一
So tell me,
也就是说
what is one-sixth plus one-sixth
六分之一加上六分之一
plus one-sixth
加上六分之一
equal to?
等于多少
Here comes the teacher.
老师来了
It's a half.
二分之一
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
are you playing with your phone?
玩手机呢
No.
没有
If you don't mind.
那我搜了
I admit.
玩了
Take it out.
拿出来
Good for you.
真会玩
Hurry up.
快点
Nice.
真不错
[OK.]
好
[Let's talk about the next question.]
我们来讲下面一个问题
[Odd numbers.]
出现奇数点
[As we just mentioned,]
我们刚刚说了
[this includes]
它的点数是
[one, three, and five.]
一点 三点和五点
[Similarly, the probability,]
同样的也是六分之一
[one-sixth plus one-sixth]
加六分之一
[is a half.]
等于二分之一
[Alright, boys and girls,]
好 同学们
[we've summarized the probability formula]
我们刚刚总结了
[for classical probability model.]
求古典概型的概率公式
[The probability value of A]
那么A的概率值
[is obtained by dividing the number of]
是A包含的
[basic events contained in A]
基本事件的个数
[by the sum of the basic events.]
除以基本事件的总和
[For example.]
打个比方
Teacher?
报告老师
What's up?
怎么了
Ma Yiming is playing with his phone.
马一鸣玩手机
Hand it out.
拿出来
Hurry up.
快点啊
Don't disturb others in class.
不要打扰其他同学上课
He was just playing,
他刚才还玩了
right in the hole of the table.
就在桌兜里
Ma Yiming,
马一鸣
don't waste the time
快点 不要耽误
of your classmates.
其他同学学习啊
You are true friends.
你们俩还真是好朋友
OK.
好
[I hope you can remember]
我刚刚讲的知识点呢
[the knowledge]
我希望同学们
[I just taught.]
都能够记住
[That's all]
以上就是
[for our lesson today.]
我们这节课的内容
[I have written the homework]
我已经把作业
on the blackboard.
写到了黑板上
OK, you're dismissed.
那我们准备下课
Please hold on!
不不不 老师
What about my phone?
手机呢
Your phone?
手机
come to me for it
你们俩这学期放假以后
during your vacation this semester.
来找我拿
Or tell your parents
或者是明天
to pick it up tomorrow.
让你们的家长过来取
Class is over.
下课
Stand up.
起立
Goodbye, teacher.
老师再见
Goodbye.
同学们再见
When did I play with my phone?
我什么时候玩手机了
If you don't,
你上课没玩手机
you must have been sleeping!
你该睡觉了吧
I slept in class,
我上课睡觉
but I didn't play with my phone.
我没玩手机啊
As your desk mate,
那我作为你的同桌
I have an obligation to supervise you.
我有义务监督你学习
Your obligation to supervise me?
你有义务监督我学习
Was I sleeping just now?
那我是不是刚才在睡觉
I didn't play with my phone,
我没有玩手机
why did you tell the teacher
那你为什么去告老师
I was playing with my phone?
我在玩手机
Now I lost my phone!
我手机都没了
Okay, come out.
好好好 你出来说
Come out.
出来说
I have to say that
我发现你这个人
you're increasingly unreasonable
真的是年龄大了
as you get older.
越来越不讲理
You're getting older!
你才年龄大
And you're unreasonable!
你才越来越不讲理了呢
What are you doing?
你干什么
It will distract your attention.
这种东西分散注意力
I have an obligation to supervise you.
我有义务监督你学习
Receiving so many letters every day,
每天收这么多信
how dare you say that to me?
你跟我说分散注意力
Alright.
也是啊
How about this?
那这样
Let's hand them over together.
我们一起交给老师
No.
不不不
Are you insane?
你有病吧
How about
那要不
we make another bet?
我们再打个赌
We race for 800 meters.
我们再跑个八百米
I will return the letters to you
你要是赢了我
if you win.
我就把信还给你
Bro,
大哥
you bet my letter
你拿我的信
on me,
跟我打赌
is it even fair?
你凭什么
If you win,
那你要是赢了我
not only will I return the letters,
我不但把信还给你
but I promise you not to mention that
而且关于你是我
you are my nephew
大外甥这事
ever since.
我也不提了
Deal.
成交
But as a bet,
但是这封信呢
this letter cannot
作为赌注
stay in your hands.
肯定是不能在你手里
Come on.
不是
Where do you want to put it?
那你想放哪儿
Let me see,
就放在
I'll put it here.
就放在这儿
No way.
不行 不行 不行
I disagree.
那不行
This is a complaint box,
这是意见箱
and it belongs to the public.
这是公家的
You dare not bet with me?
怎么 不敢赌了
How is that possible?
谁告诉你我不敢的
Put it in.
放
Put it in now.
你现在放 快放
Don't cry later,
你等会儿别哭
don't shed tears.
你别掉眼泪啊
Hurry up.
快走
After you.
你先去
I'll go to the restroom.
我去上个厕所
Why?
怎么了
Are you afraid
知道要跟我比了
of me now?
吓尿了
[I'll count to ten.]
十个数尿完啊
How's it going, Xiaohua?
怎么样了 小画
I can't open it without a key.
没钥匙打不开啊
I can't put my hands in.
手塞不进去拿不出来
How about you
要不你试试
give it a try?
你能拿出来吗
Let's turn it upside down.
咱们倒过来吧
Shall we?
不好吧
It's okay.
没关系的
What are you doing?
你们干嘛呢
Ma Yiming, why are you here?
马一鸣 你怎么在这儿
You are destroying public property.
你们俩破坏公物
Don't talk nonsense!
你才破坏公物
Ma Yiming, I don't have time
马一鸣 我现在
to fool around with you.
没时间跟你瞎闹啊
I'll report your behavior.
我去告老师
How dare you?
你 你敢
It's here.
在这儿呢
Chen Luyang!
陈璐阳
The box for voting
学生会选举投票的箱子
of Student Union is broken,
坏了
I need to borrow this one.
我要借用这个箱子
Qingtian, trust me.
晴天 你放心吧
I will win.
我一定会赢的
Are you teasing me, Ling Dong?
凌冬 耍我呢
Ling Dong!
凌冬
How dare you?
你敢耍我
Jinghui!
灰哥 灰哥
The complaint box is gone.
意见箱不见了
Don't talk nonsense to me.
别跟我扯那些没用的
An 800-meter race,
八百米
now!
现在 马上
It's really gone.
意见箱真不见了
What do you mean?
什么意思
Our complaint box has been
咱们班的意见箱
borrowed by the Student Union.
被学生会征用了
The Student Union voting
学生会选举
is about to begin now.
现在马上就要开始了
What about my letter?
不是 那我信呢
It's still inside.
信还在里边呢
[Attention please,]
各位同学请注意
[the Student Union voting]
本届学生会换届选举
[is about to begin.]
马上开始
[Everyone in Grade 10 and 11,]
请全体高一高二同学
[please gather at the gym.]
到体育馆集合
Please keep quiet!
同学们 安静一下
The voting has ended.
投票已经结束
Let's invite Mr. Zhang to
现在请张主任
count the votes for us.
为大家唱票
Chen Luyang.
陈璐阳一票
Xu Mengyu.
徐梦予一票
Hold on!
等一下
Thank you, Mr. Zhang.
谢谢你啊 主任
My pleasure.
不客气
Do you want this?
你是想要这个吗
Get down now!
先给我下来
Dear Lan Jinghui,
亲爱的兰靖灰同学
you are the most charming,
你是这所学校最迷人
handsome, humorous,
最帅气 最风趣幽默
and impressive boy in this school.
最耐人寻味的男生
Unbelievable...
让人不可思议的
Hold on.
等一下
Based on the original content, okay?
咱按原稿读好不好
[Lan Jinghui,]
兰靖灰
[you are the]
你是这所学校最蠢
[dumbest]
最笨
[and stupidest one]
最头脑简单
[with a simple mind.]
四肢发达的动物
[Sometimes I really doubt]
有的时候我真的怀疑
[if God only blocks you]
上天把智慧
[when he spreads his wisdom]
撒向人间的时候
[to the world.]
是不是唯独对你打了伞
[A naive and brainless]
像你这样
[unicellular organism like you...]
幼稚无脑的单细胞
Enough, please stop.
行了 行了 不用念了
Is it that funny?
有那么好笑吗
Is it embarrassing?
丢不丢人
Yes.
丢人
I just want to know
我现在就想知道
who wrote this!
这是谁干的
Who?
谁干的
Still laughing?
还笑
Eight rounds.
八圈了啊
Only six.
六圈
Being a class rep,
不是 你一个当班长的
why are you so poor in math?
你数学怎么那么差呀
I count one by one.
我一圈一圈数的
Keep an eye on it.
你盯着点
It's okay.
可以了 可以了 可以了
Don't make yourself so tired.
累了 累了 少跑点
class rep, as members of the class,
班长 都是同学之间的
we meet every day.
抬头不见低头见
Can you let him go?
行了吧
Nope, I must keep watch on him.
不行 我是有任务的
What a task!
辛苦班长
Have a drink.
来 喝点奶
Thank you.
谢谢
Wu Ge.
吴歌
Take this lap as the last one, OK?
最后一圈吧
I said no.
我说了 不行
You've drunk my milk!
你这不白喝我奶吗
I thought you gave me this
我本以为这是
because of our friendship.
我们同学之间的友谊
If you meant more,
如果是这样
I can return it.
我可以还给你
I've done 10 laps.
十圈了
You've completed 6 laps.
刚刚是第六圈
Now you are on the 7th lap.
现在是第七圈
And there're 3 laps left.
还剩三圈
I am now doubting
我现在严重怀疑
the authenticity of your math grades.
你数学成绩的真实性
You are slandering me.
你诬蔑我
Class rep,
班长
while you were drinking milk,
就在你刚才喝奶的时候
Jinghui had already finished
灰哥已经电光火石
in a flash.
跑完了
You see?
你听听
Don't waste time with him.
别跟他废话
Let's go.
走了 走了 走了
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
you are now in a terrible situation.
你现在已经岌岌可危了
Mr. Zhang has tasked me
主任让我来监督你
with supervising you.
是交给我的任务
What if you slack off
你要是偷懒
and get caught?
被发现怎么办
Lan Jinghui.
兰靖灰
Jesus.
你这人
Hi, Mr. Zhang.
主任好
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰 你给我
you stop right there!
你给我站住
Unbelievable.
不可思议
Mysterious.
匪夷所思
The envelope with
你说那个满天星
the baby's-breath was mine,
它明明就是我的信封
but the letter wasn't the one I wrote.
但信却不是我写的那封
It's like finding
就像一包
a spicy seasoning packet
椒盐味的干脆面里面
inside a bag of
出现了一包
savory crisps.
麻辣味的调料
Exactly.
确实
Um,
那
where is the letter then?
你说信到底会去哪儿
It couldn't have just disappeared.
它总不可能凭空消失吧
Class rep,
班长
Dong, can I help you?
凌冬同学 有什么事吗
Oh,
对了
I should call you President Chen
现在不应该叫班长了
instead of class rep.
应该叫陈主席
No, no, no.
别别别
We're just classmates.
这私底下都是同学
Don't be so formal.
别这么客气
Besides,
再说
the voting results aren't revealed yet.
这投票结果还没出来呢
Just call me class rep.
以后叫我班长就好了
Mr. Zhang just asked
刚才张主任说
you to go to his office,
让你去一趟他办公室
seemingly about
好像是
the student council election.
学生会选举的事情
Do you think he already
你说张主任现在找你
has the results
会不会是结果
and wants to
已经出来了
inform you in advance?
提前跟你说一声
Really?
是吗
The ballot box...
那我这投票箱
Well, I can take it.
没事 我帮你拿
OK, take it to the gym.
好 你直接送到体育馆
I'll go there later.
我一会儿就过来
Got it, President Chen.
放心吧 陈主席
[Dear Ling Dong,]
凌冬同学你好
[writing this letter]
写下这封信
[has taken all the courage I've gathered]
花光了我十七年来
[over my last seventeen years.]
所有的勇气
[You might find it exaggerated]
你一定会觉得我夸张
[because you are so outstanding]
像你这么优秀的人
[and always at the forefront]
永远都是在人群
[of the crowd.]
最前列的那一个
[You probably can't imagine]
一定想象不到
[how a plain, insignificant girl]
如我这般平凡
[like me]
渺小的女孩
[has strived to stand on tiptoe,]
是怎样努力踮起脚尖
[looking up to you.]
仰望着你
[To me, you're like]
你对于我来说
[the rose in "The Little Prince."]
就像小王子的玫瑰花
[I kept my secrets]
我把这些秘密
[hidden in my heart,]
都藏在心里
[which has turned into]
心中变成了一个
[a starry sky.]
发光发亮的夜空
[You are the brightest star]
你就是这片星空中
[in this sky.]
最耀眼的存在
[I strive to get closer to you,]
我想努力靠近你
[to become someone who shines]
变成可以发光的人
[and can illuminate others.]
也可以照耀到别人
[From an unnoticed girl]
一个崇拜你
[who admires you silently,]
默默无闻的女孩
[Xiao Xiaohua.]
肖小画
Jinghui,
灰哥
this letter is written to criticize you.
这封信是骂你的
Why do you piece them together?
你拼它干吗
Only when they're pieced together
只有拼好了
could I know who's criticizing me.
我才能知道是谁在骂我
and trying to set me up.
到底是谁在害我
Jinghui, you just transferred to this school.
灰哥 你刚刚来学校
Who would frame you up?
是谁会害你
That's the point.
说的可不就是嘛
I just got transferred,
我才刚刚到学校
who's setting me up?
是谁在害我
Who's scheming against me?
谁在设计我
Why would they?
他为什么要设计我
What's the reason behind it all?
原因是为什么呢
Who is trying to frame me?
是谁在陷害我
I have an idea.
我知道了
What are these?
写的啥呀
This one.
下面
Not him.
居然不是他
What are you doing?
你们俩干嘛
I've told you
我说过
don't touch my belongings.
不要乱碰我东西
I wanna make sure
我要确定
whether you wrote the letter.
你是不是写信的人
And?
结果呢
It's not you who wrote the letter.
确实不是你写的
But if I hadn't
但如果要不跟你
made a bet with you,
打赌的话
would Mr. Zhang have noticed it?
张主任他会看见吗
Because you're foolish.
是你自己笨
Ling Dong, what do you mean?
不是凌冬 你什么意思
Jinghui,
灰哥
calm down.
消消气啊
The key is to find out
现在最关键的是
who's write that letter
找出谁这么缺德
to frame you.
写那封信整你
The truth is about to come to light.
真相马上就要浮出水面了
Let's search one by one.
找 咱们一个个找
None of them.
都不是
Who else?
还有谁啊
We've searched all.
不都查了吗
Why do you look at me?
看什么看
Except you.
除了你
Did you write the letter?
你是不是自己写的
You deserve a beat.
我抽你
Well, look at the paper.
不是 你看这纸
It's the same as yours.
都是一样的呀
Do I look like a lunatic?
我有病啊
Try to harm myself?
自己整自己
You got a point.
也是啊
If the person is not our classmate,
难道不是咱们班的
it would be hard to find out.
那范围可就大了呀
Who did that?
是谁啊
I lost it.
我东西不见了
What?
什么
Who rummaged my books?
是谁动了我的练习册
My books were rummaged as well.
我的座位也被翻了
Who did that?
你们谁动我东西了
What a bad behavior!
无耻 恶劣 强盗
Ma Yiming and Lan Jinghui.
是马一鸣和兰靖灰
I saw them did that.
我刚看见他们了
Where are they?
他们人在哪儿呢
Lan Jinghui!
兰靖灰
Sorry, everyone.
不好意思啊 各位
Due to
因为我的这个
my personal issues and reasons,
个人问题和个人原因呢
it has affected
影响到了
the image of our class.
咱们班的班容班貌
I apologize to everyone.
我给大家道歉了
Sorry.
对不起
Let's share some drinks.
每个人都发饮料啊
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
how can you
你怎么可以
rummage our items?
乱动别人东西呢
That's why I apologize.
我这不道歉了吗
That rumor about Lan isn't true, right?
兰靖灰那传闻是假的吧
Yeah, how could that be possible?
对啊 怎么可能啊
One person fighting fifty people.
一个人打五十个人
We don't know for sure.
我觉得话不能这么说
What if it's true?
万一是真的呢
You've been bought off by the drinks.
两瓶饮料就把你收买了
Alright.
行了 行了
Did you drink it or not?
你们喝没喝
You know in your heart.
自己心里清楚啊
Not gossiping about him if you drank it.
喝了就别说话
Fine.
算了 算了
I said it was impossible.
我当时说了就不可能
Don't believe or spread rumors.
不信谣不传谣
I've seen plenty of students like him.
他这种人我见多了
He must have been expelled
那肯定是在别的学校
from his previous school,
待不下去了
so he was transferred.
才转到我们这儿
Don't you know that?
不都说了吗
He's transferred through many schools,
他之前转过很多个学校
always getting into fights
各种打架斗殴
and trouble.
劣迹斑斑的
With someone like him in our class,
这样的人在我们班
the entire class's reputation
整个班的水平
will be dragged down.
都会被他拉下来
I agree.
就是
I've refused this drink.
我当时说了就不要不要
But he insisted.
非要给我
It tastes terrible.
一点也不好喝
What happened?
怎么了
Who put this
谁 谁把这东西
under my books?
放到我书里的
Put what?
什么东西啊
This one?
就这个呀
It's fake.
这不假的吗
Take it away!
拿走
You seem timider than girls.
你怎么比女孩还胆小啊
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
It's mine.
我的
I walked my pet this morning.
我早上遛宠物的时候
It ran away.
它自己就跑这儿了
I don't know what happened.
我也不知道怎么回事
I don't know how...
我也不知道它怎么就
Take it away!
拿走 拿走
Help!
快来人啊
It's fake.
假的
The water tastes salty.
这水怎么是咸的呀
Salty water?
这水怎么是咸的
It can't be as sweet as my drinks.
肯定没我饮料甜吧
Lan Jinghui, are these your doings?
兰靖灰 你干的好事
Well,
不是
Too many sweets make your throat sore.
甜的吃多了齁嗓子
I added a bit of salt for you.
我帮你加点盐
The salt will balance the sweetness.
这盐甜中和一下
It's good for your health.
对不对 对身体好
You...
你
Your body
人体的机能
needs salt, doesn't it?
就需要盐分嘛
Isn't this good?
这不挺好吗 没事啊
Or I can get you some water.
或者我再去给你买瓶水
Come in.
进
Ms. Fang, what do you need from me?
方老师找我什么事
What are these?
这什么
Complaints from your classmates.
同学们的意见
All against you.
全部都是与你有关的
Ms. Fang, you said
方老师 您不是说
you wouldn't check the complaint box.
您不看意见箱吗
If I want to,
我想看的时候
I will.
自然就会看了
I unexpectedly found that
而且我不看不知道啊
the students are
因为你一个人
unprecedentedly united because of you.
咱们班这么空前团结
They're just being petty.
他们就是小心眼
Conflicts among
同学之间
classmates are normal, right?
哪有不闹矛盾的对不对
Tattling to the teacher is so childish.
告老师这事多低级
You need more self-reflections, right?
我看你是检查还没写够
No, I've written enough.
不是 写得够够的
That means
那就说明
the previous one wasn't sincere enough.
之前检查的力度不够
This time,
这样
write a 3,000-word reflection.
这次呢 三千字
Write it thoroughly
你要好好地写
and seriously,
认真地写
including the causes,
把原因到结果
the results
再到改正过程
and the correction measures.
都写出来
Show me your sincerity.
让我看到你的诚意
Can you do that?
可以吗
Ms. Fang,
老师
is there any room for negotiation?
还有回旋的余地吗
Nope.
没有
Jinghui,
灰哥
It hard to catch my breath with this.
这玩意有点喘不上气来
Let's put it off.
撤了吧
OK, it's not necessary.
是 形式感是有点强
Let's deal with them one by one.
我念一个你卸一个 来
So many to deal with, right?
这工程量可就大了去了
Can you recognize the bikes of them?
这些人的车你都认识吗
Of course, they are my classmates
这么多年同学了
for many years.
那当然
Good.
非常好
Chen Luyang first.
第一个 陈璐阳
And Liu Shu.
刘姝
She's a girl.
女孩就算了
Let her go.
算了 算了
OK?
算了 算了 算了
Li Ruosi.
李若丝
Here
这儿
And?
还有谁
Ling Dong.
凌冬
Who?
谁
Ling Dong didn't write any complaints.
凌冬没给你投意见吧
He instigated them.
那也是他唆使的
Jinghui,
灰哥
You have a prejudice against him.
我看你就是对他有偏见
He has a "pride" against me.
他还对我傲慢呢
Hurry up!
快点
Are you sure?
你确定
I'm sure.
我确定
OK, here we go.
我真放了啊
The semester has started,
你说这开学了
why don't you introduce me
你不带我去你们学校
to the basketball team of this school?
篮球队领教一下
Training hasn't started yet.
还没开始训练呢
Don't worry.
放心吧
Our team's skill level
我们队的水平
is top-notch.
必须是这个
Don't brag.
你别吹牛啊
I transferred here
我特意转学过来
specifically to play basketball.
就是为了打篮球来的
What about
不过那个凌冬
Ling Dong?
什么情况
He's really something.
他可厉害了
Um, he's a typical
我告诉你
"triple high": high scores,
他就是典型的三高
highly aloof, and high intelligence.
高分 高冷 高智商
He's the superstar at school,
他在学校巨出名
consistently a top student,
从小到大都是三好学生
and wins awards left and right.
拿奖拿到手软
He's way ahead of you.
可比你强多了
Then which side are you on?
那你是哪头的
You praise him!
还夸他
I came to this school
我来这个学校
for you.
可是为了你
You just said
你刚才不是说
you transferred to this school
你来这个学校
to play basketball.
是为了打篮球
To understand the situation in detail,
详细了解一下状况
I must know my opponent well,
你得做到知己知彼
then I can defeat him easily.
百战不殆
Jinghui,
灰哥
It's your first day at this school.
你这刚来学校第一天
He's your desk mate.
作为同桌呢
If it's not something major between you,
你俩要是没啥大事
just let it go.
就算了吧
If he doesn't bother me, I won't bother him.
人不犯我 我不犯人
But if he does,
人若犯我
I'll be a nuisance for sure.
我必烦人
Then you try to bother him,
你烦他去
not me.
你烦我干啥